The child wants to climb that slide or the ladder, and you're saying, "Be careful."
What does that mean to the child, "Be careful"? What is the child supposed to do except maybe freeze?
Whereas if you said, "That ladder is quite tall. You need to make sure, you know, you're holding the side railings."
Now you've given him something very specific to do.
And, you know, they learn through their mistakes. That's the whole thing about risky play and the importance of it.
Instead of saying, "If you run on the road, you'll fall and hurt yourself,"
you say, "You may fall if you run fast on the road and you'll hurt yourself."
If they don't listen, they'll hurt themselves.
That's the logical consequence that happened.
That's how children learn. That's how children can evaluate. That's how children can make choices.